The game you couldn't put down. The story you couldn't make up.
Tetris is a thriller, history, drama film directed by Jon S. Baird.
In 1988, American video game salesman Henk Rogers
discovers the video game Tetris.
When he sets out to bring the game to the world, he enters a dangerous
web of lies and corruption behind the Iron Curtain.
Henk Rogers, played by Taron Egerton.
Alexey Pajitnov, played by Nikita Efremov.
Sasha, played by Sofia Lebedeva.
Kevin Maxwell, played by Anthony Boyle.
Howard Lincoln, played by Ben Miles.
Minoru Arakawa, played by Ken Yamamura.
Tetris is a 2023 biographical thriller film based on true events around the race to license and
patent the video game Tetris from Soviet Russia in the late 1980s during the Cold War.
It was directed by Jon S.
Baird and written by Noah Pink.
The film stars Taron Egerton, Nikita Efremov, Sofia Lebedeva, and Anthony Boyle.
The plot follows Henk Rogers of Bullet-Proof Software, who becomes interested in the
game Tetris, created by Alexey Pajitnov, during an electronics show.
Desperate to obtain handheld console rights for Nintendo, he takes trips between Japan, the
United States, and Russia to win legal battles over the game's ownership.
Development of Tetris began in July 2020.
Filming began in Glasgow in December 2020, including Glasgow Prestwick Airport.
In February 2021, filming took place in Aberdeen at locations
including the University of Aberdeen's Zoology Building.
Filming took place for 7 days in and around the former (RAF)
military base at Balado in Perth & Kinross.
Production wrapped in early March 2021.
Tetris premiered at the SXSW Film Festival on March 15, 2023,
and was released on March 31, by Apple TV+.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics
and was praised by Pajitnov and Rogers.
The film explores themes of video game, nintendo, cold
war, based on true story, salesman.
The tone is emotional and intense.